♪
( Kirito grunting )
Alice: LET GO OF MY HAND
THIS INSTANT, SINNER!
I WOULD RATHER DIE
THAN BE SAVED BY YOU.
I WILL NOT BEAR
THE DISGRACE OF IT! ( grunts )
Kirito: HEY! STOP!
DON’T, YOU IDIOT!
WHAT’S SUICIDE GONNA DO?
NOTHING, THAT’S WHAT,
SO SUCK IT UP,
ACT LIKE A KNIGHT,
AND QUIT BEIN’ AN IDIOT!
Alice: HOW DARE YOU,
A COMMON CRIMINAL, INSULT ME?!
I DEMAND AN APOLOGY.
Kirito: OH, SHUT UP!
I CALLED YOU AN IDIOT,
’CAUSE YOU’RE ACTIN’
LIKE AN IDIOT, IDIOT!
LISTEN! IF I LET GO
AND YOU DIE, THEN WHAT?
EUGEO’S STILL IN THE CATHEDRAL,
AND HE’S ON HIS WAY
UP TO THE PONTIFEX,
AND IT’S YOUR JOB TO STOP HIM,
YOU IDIOT!
( Alice grumbles )
Kirito: INSTEAD OF CHECKIN’ OUT,
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
SHOULD BE THINKIN’
HOW TO GET BACK IN, BUT NOT YOU.
YOU’RE SO DUMB,
YOU FORGOT YOUR PRIORITIES,
AND THAT’S WHY YOU’RE AN IDIOT!
Alice: LOOK HERE.
I WON’T ALLOW A ROGUE LIKE YOU
TO INSULT ME ANY FURTHER.
THAT SAID, YOUR WORDS HAVE
A CERTAIN LOGIC TO THEM.
HOWEVER, DEATH IS MORE TOLERABLE
THAN BEING SAVED OUT OF PITY,
AND LETTING ME FALL
WOULD BENEFIT YOUR CAUSE,
SO WHY DON’T YOU?
EXPLAIN WHY I MUST ACCEPT
THIS SITUATION!
Kirito: I’LL TRY.
( singing in Japanese )
♪
♪ PROUD OF MYSELF ♪
Kirito: EUGEO AND ME,
WE DIDN’T BREAK IN AND
GET THIS FAR UP THE CATHEDRAL
JUST TO DESTROY
THE AXIOM CHURCH.
WE KNOW THE DARK TERRITORY’S
GONNA INVADE THE HUMAN EMPIRE,
AND WE WANNA PROTECT IT,
SAME AS YOU.
YOU’RE ONE OF THE MOST POWERFUL
INTEGRITY KNIGHTS AROUND,
AND, IF I LET YOU DIE,
WE LOSE A VALUABLE ALLY.
- ( Alice gasps )
- Kirito: WE CAN’T AFFORD THAT.
Alice: WHY SHOULD
I BELIEVE YOU?
YOU VIOLATED
THE GRAVEST TABOO OF ALL,
SPILLING THE BLOOD
OF A FELLOW HUMAN
AND CUTTING THEM DOWN.
Kirito: THAT’S TRUE.
BUT THE AXIOM CHURCH
AND THE TABOO INDEX ARE WRONG.
EUGEO AND I HAD A GOOD REASON
TO ATTACK RAIOS AND HUMBERT.
THE LAWS LET
UPPER-CLASS NOBLES LIKE THEM
DO WHATEVER THEY WANT
TO INNOCENT PEOPLE.
THOSE BASTARDS
WERE GONNA RAPE RONIE AND TIESE
AND GET AWAY WITH IT.
DO YOU THINK THAT’S RIGHT?
DO YOU THINK THAT’S FAIR?!
WELL, IS IT?
ANSWER ME! IS IT RIGHT?!
Alice: THE LAW IS THE LAW.
A CRIME IS A CRIME.
IF THE PEOPLE
ARE ALLOWED TO DECIDE
WHAT IS RIGHT AND WRONG
ACCORDING TO THEIR NEEDS,
HOW WILL WE MAINTAIN ORDER
IN THE LAND?
Kirito: YEAH, WELL,
ADMINISTRATOR CAME UP
WITH ALL THE LAWS,
SO WHO DECIDES
IF SHE’S RIGHT OR WRONG?
YOUR GOD?
IF I’M SUCH A SINNER,
THEN HOW COME
I HAVEN’T BEEN FRIED
BY A BOLT OF LIGHTNING BY NOW?
Alice: SIMPLE.
IT IS THE WILL OF STACIA,
AND WE KNIGHTS ENFORCE HER WILL.
WE ARE HER DIVINE SERVANTS.
Kirito: ALL YOU KNIGHTS
ENFORCE ARE LIES,
AND ME AND EUGEO
CAME HERE TO PROVE IT!
IF WE DEFEAT ADMINISTRATOR,
WE’LL END HER TYRANNY.
WE’RE NOT THE BAD GUYS!
IF WE WERE,
I’D HAVE LET YOU FALL.
( wall creaking )
( gasps )
IT’S COMIN’ LOOSE!
STICK YOUR SWORD IN THE WALL,
OR WE DIE!
( groaning )
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR? DO IT!
MINE’S ABOUT TO COME OUT! HURRY!
( gasps )
( Alice grunting )
( Kirito gasps )
( yelps )
( sword stabs )
Alice: I DID NOT
SAVE YOU, SINNER.
I RETURNED THE FAVOR, IS ALL.
BESIDES, OUR DUEL
HAS YET TO BE DECIDED.
Kirito: IF WE SURVIVE.
OH, WELL.
AT LEAST WE’RE EVEN NOW.
I GOT AN IDEA,
IF YOU WANNA HEAR.
WE CAN’T HANG HERE ALL DAY.
OUR ARMS’LL GET TIRED.
BUT IF WE WORK TOGETHER,
WE CAN FIND A WAY BACK IN.
SO, LIKE, WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE CALL A TRUCE ’TIL THEN?
- Alice: A TRUCE?
- Kirito: YEAH.
WE CAN’T BREAK THE WALL,
SO WE’LL HAVE TO CLIMB.
IT’LL BE EASIER
IF WE HELP EACH OTHER.
Alice: YOU SAY,
"HELP EACH OTHER."
HOW DO YOU PROPOSE WE DO THAT?
Kirito: IF ONE OF US
STARTS TO FALL,
THE OTHER STOPS ’EM. THAT’S ALL.
IF WE HAD A ROPE, WE COULD
USE IT AS A SAFETY LINE.
I DIDN’T BRING ONE, THOUGH.
Alice: I HATE TO ADMIT IT,
BUT THAT DOES SOUND LOGICAL.
VERY WELL.
HOWEVER, THE MOMENT
WE SET FOOT INSIDE AGAIN,
I WILL CUT YOU DOWN.
TRUCE OR NO,
DO NOT FORGET THAT.
Kirito: I’LL TRY NOT TO.
Alice: NOW, THEN,
YOU SAID WE NEEDED ROPE.
SYSTEM CALL. FORM OBJECT.
CHANGE SHAPE.
Kirito: W-WAS THAT
THE MATTER CONVERSION ART?!
Alice: DID YOU
NOT HEAR WHAT I SAID?
I CHANGED
THE SHAPE OF AN OBJECT.
ONLY THE PONTIFEX
CAN USE THE FORMAL ARTS
TO CHANGE AN OBJECT’S
PROPERTIES, YOU DOLT.
Kirito: SORRY, MA’AM.
♪
( sighs )
( gasps )
( swallows )
HEY, UM, I JUST THOUGHT
OF SOMETHING ELSE.
Alice: WHAT IS IT?
Kirito: IT’S ABOUT
THAT DRAGON OF YOURS.
CAN’T YOU, LIKE,
SUMMON IT TO COME GET US?
Alice: MINE CANNOT FLY FURTHER
THAN THE LANDING PLATFORMS
ON THE 30th FLOOR.
NO DRAGON CAN. EVEN MY UNCL--
PARDON. EVEN THE COMMANDER’S
IS NOT ALLOWED.
THE UPPER FLOORS ARE OFF LIMITS.
EVEN THE BIRDS STAY AWAY.
THE PONTIFEX HERSELF MADE IT SO.
SHE CAST A FORMAL ART,
ONE SO ADVANCED,
I DO NOT EVEN KNOW IT.
Kirito: OH, WELL.
I GUESS THAT LEAVES US
WITH THREE OPTIONS, THEN.
GO UP OR DOWN
OR BUST THROUGH THE WALL AGAIN.
Alice: THE THIRD OPTION IS OUT.
THE CATHEDRAL WALLS ARE ENDOWED
WITH NEARLY INFINITE LIFE,
AND, AS YOU SAW,
THEY REGENERATE QUICKLY.
Kirito: PERFECT.
ALL RIGHT,
I’M THINKING WE SHOULD CLIMB.
DO YOU KNOW IF THERE’S ANYWHERE
UP TOP WHERE WE CAN GET IN?
Alice: THERE IS.
THE MORNING STAR LOOKOUT
IS ON THE 95th FLOOR.
THERE ARE NO WALLS,
JUST PILLARS.
IF WE CAN CLIMB UP THAT FAR,
WE CAN EASILY GET BACK IN.
THAT SAID, IF WE MANAGE
TO SURVIVE THE CLIMB AND GET IN,
OUR TRUCE IS OFF,
AND I WILL SLAY YOU.
Kirito: I KNOW.
I DIDN’T FORGET ABOUT OUR DEAL.
( sighs ) SO ARE YOU OKAY
WITH CLIMBING UP, OR WHAT?
Alice: YES. GOING UP
IS MORE PRACTICAL THAN DOWN,
BUT HOW DO YOU PLAN
ON SCALING A SHEER WALL?
IT WON’T BE EASY.
Kirito: SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE METALLIC ELEMENT.
WEDGE SHAPE!
♪
( grunting )
Alice: IS THAT
SAFE TO STAND ON?
Kirito: SEEMS TO BE, FOR NOW.
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE METALLIC ELEMENT.
( grunts )
YOU KNOW, I THINK THIS’LL WORK.
WELL? DON’T JUST HANG THERE.
DO WHAT I DID.
Alice: I CANNOT.
Kirito: HUH?
WH-WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
Alice: I SAID I CANNOT!
Kirito: YEAH, I HEARD THAT,
BUT WHAT DO YOU MEAN, YOU CAN’T?
IF I CAN MAKE A WEDGE, YOU CAN.
AND YOU’RE SO STRONG,
YOU SHOULDN’T HAVE
ANY PROBLEM HOISTING--
Alice: THAT IS NOT WHAT I MEANT!
I HAVE NEVER BEEN IN A SITUATION
LIKE THIS BEFORE TODAY.
A-AT THE RISK OF SOUNDING WEAK,
IT IS ALL I CAN MANAGE
TO JUST HANG ON.
I CANNOT CLIMB UP
ONTO SUCH A SLENDER STEP.
Kirito: NO WORRIES. HOW ’BOUT
IF I PULL YOU UP TO THE BAR?
WOULD THAT WORK
FOR YOU INSTEAD?
Alice: I WOULD APPRECIATE IT.
Kirito: OKAY. FIRST I’M
GONNA TAKE UP THE SLACK.
HERE GOES!
♪
I’M READY. GO ON,
AND PULL YOUR SWORD OUT.
( grunts )
( Alice gasps )
♪
( shuddering )
Kirito: GRAB THE WALL
TO BALANCE!
ALL RIGHT, I’M GONNA CLIMB UP
A LITTLE HIGHER NOW.
I’LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN I’M READY.
Alice: PLEASE BE CAREFUL.
Kirito: ALWAYS.
( waves crashing )
( Rinko gasps )
- HEY, ASUNA.
- Asuna: HUH?
Rinko: HOW’S YOUR FISH?
I BET THEY CAUGHT IT RIGHT
OFF THE SIDE OF THE TURTLE.
Asuna: YEAH, MAYBE THEY DID.
OR MAYBE THEY BROUGHT IT.
Rinko: WHO?
HMM. I DOUBT IT.
DOESN’T LOOK
LIKE A FISHING BOAT.
IT’S GOT WAY TOO MANY ANTENNAE.
Asuna: IS IT A BATTLESHIP?
Nakanishi: NO. IT’S JAPANESE.
WE DON’T HAVE BATTLESHIPS
IN SERVICE ANYMORE.
MS. YUUKI, DR. KOJIRO, MORNING.
Asuna: GOOD MORNING.
Rinko: GOOD MORNING,
MR. NAKANISHI.
IF THAT’S NOT A WARSHIP,
IS IT S.D.F.?
Nakanishi: M.S.D.F.,
AND "ESCORT SHIP"
IS THE OFFICIAL DESIGNATION.
THE ONE OUT THERE
IS THE "DD119 ASAHI."
SHE’S A FIVE-TON,
GENERAL-PURPOSE VESSEL.
SHE’S ONE OF TWO ESCORT SHIPS
IN SERVICE.
( women giggling )
Nakanishi: HER SISTER SHIP
IS THE "SHIRANUI"...
Asuna: HEY, IT LOOKS
LIKE IT’S MOVING AWAY NOW.
Nakanishi: ...SECOND GENERATION
OF THEIR CLASS. EH?
( sighs )
PARDON ME.
LIEUTENANT COLONEL KIKUOKA?
I JUST SAW THE "ASAHI"
CHANGING COURSE TO THE WEST.
WASN’T SHE
SUPPOSED TO STAY WITH US
UNTIL 1200,
DAY AFTER TOMORROW?
YES, SIR. RIGHT AWAY.
EXCUSE ME, LADIES.
SOMETHING’S COME UP.
Rinko: HMM. IT MUST BE
SOMETHING IMPORTANT.
Asuna: YEAH.
( sighs )
( Kirito grunting )
SYSTEM CALL.
GENERATE METALLIC ELEMENT.
Alice: THE LIGHT.
( Kirito sighs )
Alice: GENERATING CONTAINERS
USES UP A SIGNIFICANT AMOUNT
OF SACRED POWER,
AND ONCE SOLUS SETS,
WE’LL BE LUCKY IF WE
CAN CREATE ONE BAR AN HOUR.
( Kirito sighs )
Alice: HOW HIGH UP
DO YOU THINK WE ARE NOW?
Kirito: UM...
I THINK WE’RE ALREADY PAST
THE 85th FLOOR.
Alice: THE 95th FLOOR
IS STILL QUITE A LONG WAY OFF.
Kirito: YEAH, AND CLIMBING’S
GONNA BE EVEN MORE DANGEROUS
ONCE IT’S TOO DARK TO SEE.
EH? HEY, CHECK IT OUT!
THERE’S SOMETHING ON THAT LEDGE.
♪
Alice: THEY LOOK
LIKE STATUES FROM HERE,
WHICH IS ODD.
NO ONE BELOW CAN SEE THEM.
Kirito: OH, WELL. THEIR LOSS,
BUT MAYBE WE CAN REST ON ’EM.
THEY LOOK LIKE
THEY’RE ABOUT SIX METER--
SIX MELS AWAY.
WE’RE GONNA NEED TWO MORE BARS.
Alice: YOU ONLY NEED TWO,
YOU SAY?
VERY WELL, THEN.
I WAS SAVING IT
FOR AN EMERGENCY.
IT APPEARS THIS WOULD BE ONE.
FORM OBJECT. WEDGE SHAPE.
HERE. USE THESE.
Kirito: THANKS! I OWE YOU.
( grunting )
GET READY. I’M PULLIN’ YOU UP.
Alice: RIGHT.
Kirito: YOU GOOD?
Alice: I’M FINE.
Kirito: OH.
♪
( Alice gasps )
NO.
Kirito: OH, MY GOD.
THAT SURE IS ONE UGLY STATUE.
( gasps )
( creature growls )
Alice: IT’S FROM
THE DARK TERRITORY!
( creature roars )
Kirito: ALICE!
♪
ALICE!
( creature 2 roars )
( creature 1 roars )
( Kirito gasps )
( grunts )
( creature 1 roars )
Kirito: DRAW YOUR SWORD! HURRY!
THERE’S TWO MORE COMIN’!
( creature 2 roars )
( Alice gasping )
Kirito: ALICE!
( creatures growling )
Kirito: WE’RE SCREWED
IF THEY ATTACK AT ONCE.
WHAT THE HELL’S UP WITH HER?!
( sighs )
ALICE!
- ALICE!
- ( Alice gasps )
Kirito: HANG ON
AS TIGHT AS YOU CAN!
Alice: N-NOW, JUST A MOMENT.
Kirito: I’LL APOLOGIZE LATER,
IF WE SURVIVE!
GET READY!
ONE, TWO...
- THREE!
- ( Alice whimpers )
( Kirito yells )
( Alice screams )
( grunts )
( yells )
( Kirito yells )
( groans )
Alice: WHAT WERE YOU THINKING,
YOU IDIOT?!
HAVE YOU LOST YOUR MIND?!
Kirito: I DIDN’T HAVE
ANY OTHER CHOICE.
I HAD TO ACT.
WE’LL TALK LATER.
HERE THEY COME!
( Alice gasps )
( creatures growling )
♪
( Kirito gasps )
Alice: THERE IS NO DOUBT.
( gasps ) BUT WHY ARE THEY HERE?
Kirito: I WAS WONDERING
WHEN YOU’D SNAP OUT OF IT.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THESE MONSTERS ARE?
Alice: YES, I DO, INDEED.
THEY ARE FAMILIARS
FROM THE DARK TERRITORY,
CONJURED FROM LUMPS
OF CORRUPT SOIL
BY SORCERERS
WHO PRACTICE THE DARK ARTS.
SUCH DISGUSTING THINGS.
WE CALL THESE CREATURES MINIONS.
Kirito: THAT FIGURES.
BUT WHY ARE THEY HERE?
THIS IS THE HOLIEST PLACE
IN THE LAND,
AND THEY’RE
JUST HANGING OUT ON IT.
Alice: I’D LIKE
TO KNOW WHY AS WELL!
THEY SHOULD NOT BE HERE
FOULING THE VERY SYMBOL
OF ALL THAT IS GOOD.
I CANNOT BELIEVE
THEY ESCAPED THE NOTICE
OF THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS
TO ROOST
ON THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL,
WHERE EVEN THE BIRDS
CANNOT LAND.
IT’S UNREAL.
Kirito: YEAH, WELL,
NOT IF ADMINISTRATOR
WANTED THESE SUCKERS HERE.
I DON’T KNOW WHY SHE WOULD,
BUT IT’S POSSIBLE.
AT THIS POINT,
IT WOULDN’T SURPRISE ME.
WATCH IT! THE OTHER TWO
ARE COMING AROUND AGAIN!
Alice: I KNOW. THIS IS
NOT MY FIRST TIME IN BATTLE.
( minions growling )
♪
Alice: DO YOU NEED ASSISTANCE
WITH THAT ONE?
Kirito: NOPE! I CAN HANDLE HIM!
( yells )
( Alice gasps )
( Kirito sighs ) YOU OKAY?
Alice: I AM.
I WAS JUST THINKING
HOW STRANGE YOUR MOVES ARE.
IF YOU PERFORMED THEM
AT THE MIDSUMMER FESTIVAL,
YOU WOULD ATTRACT
QUITE AN AUDIENCE.
Kirito:
THANKS FOR THE COMPLIMENT.
HANG ON. HAVE YOU BEEN TO
THE MIDSUMMER FESTIVAL BEFORE?
I THOUGHT
IT WAS ONLY FOR COMMONERS.
EVEN KIDS FROM THE UPPER-CLASS
FAMILIES STAYED AWAY,
AT LEAST THE ONES I WAS
GOING TO THE ACADEMY WITH.
Alice: DO NOT MENTION ME
IN THE SAME BREATH
AS THOSE SO-CALLED NOBLES.
I’VE SEEN IT. I--
I’VE BEEN...
Kirito: A-ALICE?
Alice: NO.
I HAVE ONLY HEARD OF IT.
ONE OF THE PRIESTS
MUST HAVE TOLD ME OF IT.
WE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS,
WE ARE PROHIBITED FROM MINGLING
WITH THE TOWNSFOLK,
EXCEPT IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
Kirito: WHAT?
Alice: MINION BLOOD
CARRIES DISEASE.
YOU SHOULD WIPE IT OFF.
Kirito: HUH? OH.
( Alice gasps )
NO, NOT LIKE THAT!
( Kirito gasps )
Alice: HONESTLY! COULD A MAN
BE ANY MORE THOUGHTLESS?
ARE YOU SO UNCOUTH, YOU DO
NOT EVEN HAVE A HANDKERCHIEF?
Kirito: N-NO, I DON’T.
Alice: AS I THOUGHT. USE MINE.
Kirito: UH...
THANKS. I APPRECIATE IT.
Alice: UH...
( scoffs )
I WOULD LIKE IT
WASHED AND RETURNED
BEFORE I SLAY YOU.
( Kirito chuckles )
♪
Eugeo: NOW THAT I THINK OF IT,
EVER SINCE I MET KIRITO
TWO YEARS AGO,
HE’S ALWAYS BEEN WITH ME.
I’VE FORGOTTEN
WHAT IT’S LIKE TO BE ALONE.
I HOPE HE’S OKAY.
KNOWING HIM, I’M SURE HE IS.
HE’S PROBABLY
CLIMBING THE TOWER,
LOOKING FOR A WAY IN
ALONG WITH ALICE.
THE 90th FLOOR.
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT
IS IN THERE.
HERE GOES.
( door grinding )
IT’S A GIANT BATH.
- ( water splashes )
- ( gasps )
Knight: EASY, KID.
I NEED TO STRETCH
BEFORE WE START.
I JUST GOT BACK
FROM PATROLLING THE BORDERLANDS.
RIDING THAT DRAGON NONSTOP
SURE DOES A NUMBER ON THE BODY.
( Eugeo gasps )
( Knight sighs )
( chuckles )
Singer: ♪ OH, EVERYTHING
TURNS TO ASH, TO ASH ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ AND EVERYTHING
TURNS TO DUST, TO DUST ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ FORGET-ME-NOT ♪